Nelson Orellana

🖀 Lyn, Ontario, Canada 🛕 nelson.mycareers@gmail.com 🖫 1-519-778-9726 🛗 in/naorella 🗘 naorella.github.io/

Summary

GIS Analyst with 5 years of experience in data analysis and visualization, database management, and data transformation. Skilled in raster image segmentation and in data classification with machine learning. Proven collaborator in designing cartographic maps and databases based on user specification.

Experience

Freelance Programmer

January 2024-Present

- Conducted thorough code reviews for multiple projects monthly, identifying and rectifying critical issues and optimizing code efficiency, which led to an increase in overall application performance.
- Conducted supervised learning on machine learning algorithms, enhancing their accuracy and utilizing Python libraries such as TensorFlow and scikit-learn for model optimization.
- Developed custom scripts tailored to client requirements, leveraging Python libraries such as Pandas and NumPy, which automated repetitive tasks.
- Configured and managed virtual Linux machines to run independent tests of code before pushing to production, utilizing automation tools to ensure consistent environment resets and improve testing efficiency.

Keyholder Supervisor

Lindt

June 2018 - September 2023, Waterloo, ON

- Trained new employees on company policies, procedures and work ethics.
- Collaborated closely with upper management to develop strategies for improving operational efficiency within the store.
- Created monthly analysis of store key performance indicators to be presented to upper management, with clear outlines and goals for improving sales metrics

Water and Wastewater Systems Planning Co-op

City of Hamilton Public Works

September 2021 – December 2021, Hamilton, ON

- Implemented automated workflows for production of large scale map products.
- Constructed geospatial databases from paper maps or online sources with accuracy levels meeting project requirements.
- Collaborated with other departments to properly define user needs for new projects.
- Utilized data analysis to visualize demographic data according to project need.

Education

Bachelor of Environmental Studies, Geomatics

Minor in Computing • University of Waterloo • Waterloo, ON

Skills

Data Analysis: Python, Jupyter Notebooks, Excel GIS: ArcGIS, QGIS, GeoPandas, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn

Data Management: PostgreSQL, Git, Bash Scripting Docker: Docker files, Docker Compose, GitHub Actions

Programming: C, C++, PHP, Javascript, HTML/CSS, 3D Engines: Blender, Godot